{
  "reference_number": "11010",
  "clauses": [
    {
      "question": "1. What process should the Government use to set a new emissions reduction target in legislation?",
      "question_index": 0,
      "answer": "The Government sets a 2050 target in legislation now",
      "answer_index": 0,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "2. If the Government sets a 2050 target now, which is the best target for New Zealand?",
      "question_index": 1,
      "answer": "Net Zero Carbon Dioxide - Reducing net carbon dioxide emissions to zero by 2050",
      "answer_index": 13,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "3. How should New Zealand meet its targets?",
      "question_index": 2,
      "answer": "Domestic emissions reductions (including from new forest planting) and using some emissions reductions from overseas (international carbon units) that have strong environmental safeguards",
      "answer_index": 2,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "4. Should the Zero Carbon Bill allow the 2050 target to be revised if circumstances change?",
      "question_index": 3,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "5. The Government proposes that three emissions budgets of five years each (i.e. covering the next 15 years) be in place at any given time. Do you agree with this proposal?",
      "question_index": 15,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "6. Should the Government be able to alter the last emissions budget (i.e. furthest into the future)?",
      "question_index": 4,
      "answer": "No - emissions budgets should not be able to be changed",
      "answer_index": 9,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "7. Should the Government have the ability to review and adjust the second emissions budget within a specific range under exceptional circumstances? See p36 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 5,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "8. Do you agree with the considerations we propose that the Government and the Climate Change Commission take into account when advising on and setting budgets? See p44 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 6,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "Need to consider behavioural changes right across all human activity especially in leisure, recreation and sport. Sport and recreation\n\nis a major example where land use, infrastructure, transport and events has not been investigated and fully considered in its carbon\nuse. Sport is a large cultural social impact activity yet operates under little regard for the environment and large carbon use from land\n\nuse, clothing to activities “as of right” under a “leisure freedom” not questioned. The growth of artificial “plastic” surfaces for\nspecialised ball sport is a specific example illustrating that only elite groups will be able to engage in future? There will be major\n\nchanges and recreation displacement in future. The sport and recreation community has not yet fully engaged with these issues.\nBehavioural and associated philosophical cultural changes need to be added to the list."
    },
    {
      "question": "9. Should the Zero Carbon Bill require Governments to set out plans within a certain timeframe to achieve the emissions budgets?",
      "question_index": 7,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "10. What are the most important issues for the Government to consider in setting plans to meet budgets? For example, who do we need to work with, what else needs to be considered?",
      "question_index": 8,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "10 Promoting the need for change of behaviour change at an individual level as the main priority. Local government needs to take a\n\nmajor responsibility but also all NGOs and community groups There will be environmental conflicts and these need to be identified.\nE.g moving towards a pest free NZ by 2050 will require a high use of carbon. However it can be reduced with the evidence\nsuggesting biodiversity may increase in the long term if evolutionary biology and some extinction is accepted."
    },
    {
      "question": "11. The Government has proposed that the Climate Change Commission advises on and monitors New Zealand's progress towards its goals. Do you agree with these functions? See p42 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 9,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "12. What role do you think the Climate Change Commission should have in relation to the New Zealand Emissions Trading Scheme (NZ ETS)?",
      "question_index": 10,
      "answer": "Makes decisions itself in respect of the number of units available in the NZ ETS",
      "answer_index": 10,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "13. The Government has proposed that Climate Change Commissioners need to have a range of essential and desirable expertise. Do you agree with the proposed expertise? See p45 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 11,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "Needs more behavioural expertise and a social philosopher. Far too economically and engineering orientated."
    },
    {
      "question": "14. Do you think the Zero Carbon Bill should cover adapting to climate change?",
      "question_index": 12,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "Need to consider behavioural changes right across all human activity especially in leisure, recreation and sport."
    },
    {
      "question": "15. The Government has proposed a number of new functions to help us adapt to climate change. Do you agree with the proposed functions? See p47 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 13,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "Will be major not possble impacts on our health, biodiversity and culture over time. Leisure needs to be also included"
    },
    {
      "question": "16. Should we explore setting up a targeted adaptation reporting power that could see some organisations share information on their exposure to climate change risks?",
      "question_index": 14,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "Do you have any other comments you'd like to make?",
      "question_index": 16,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "Sport and recreation is a major example where land use, sea level rise, infrastructure, transport and events has not been investigated\nand fully considered in its carbon use. Sport is a large cultural social impact activity yet operates under little regard for the\n\nenvironment and large carbon use from land use, clothing to activities “as of right” under a “leisure freedom” not questioned. The\ngrowth of artificial “plastic” surfaces for specialised ball sport is a specific example illustrating that only elite groups will be able to\n\nengage in future? There will be major changes and recreation displacement in future. The sport and recreation community has not\nyet fully engaged with these issues."
    }
  ]
}
